{"text": "The new policy will affect all employees of the company , including those in the top management , said a spokesperson for the company .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 48, "subj_end": 55, "obj": "spokesperson", "obj_start": 105, "obj_end": 117, "relation": "org:top_members/employees"}
{"text": "The government has announced a new package of measures to support small and medium-sized enterprises ( SMEs ) , including tax breaks and subsidies for employee training , said a spokesperson for the Ministry of Finance .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Ministry of Finance", "subj_start": 199, "subj_end": 218, "obj": "spokesperson", "obj_start": 178, "obj_end": 190, "relation": "org:top_members/employees"}
{"text": "The company 's board of directors has approved a new strategy for expanding into new markets , said the CEO in a statement .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "CEO", "obj_start": 104, "obj_end": 107, "relation": "org:top_members/employees"}
{"text": "The government has appointed a new head of the National Health Service ( NHS ) , who will be responsible for overseeing the implementation of the new healthcare reforms , said a spokesperson for the Department of Health .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Department of Health", "subj_start": 199, "subj_end": 219, "obj": "spokesperson", "obj_start": 178, "obj_end": 190, "relation": "org:top_members/employees"}
{"text": "The government has announced a new package of measures to support the development of renewable energy , including tax breaks and subsidies for research and development , said a spokesperson for the Ministry of Energy .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Ministry of Energy", "subj_start": 198, "subj_end": 216, "obj": "spokesperson", "obj_start": 177, "obj_end": 189, "relation": "org:top_members/employees"}
{"text": "The company 's top engineers have been working on a new product line that will be launched next year , said the CEO in a statement .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "CEO", "obj_start": 112, "obj_end": 115, "relation": "org:top_members/employees"}
{"text": "The government has appointed a new head of the National Security Agency ( NSA ) , who will be responsible for overseeing the agency 's intelligence gathering and analysis activities , said a spokesperson for the White House .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "White House", "subj_start": 212, "subj_end": 223, "obj": "spokesperson", "obj_start": 191, "obj_end": 203, "relation": "org:top_members/employees"}
{"text": "The Christian Coalition of America has endorsed President Bush's tax cut plan as a step towards fulfilling the biblical mandate to be good stewards of their wealth .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "Christian Coalition of America", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 34, "obj": "Christian", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 13, "relation": "org:political/religious_affiliation"}
{"text": "The Southern Baptist Convention is the largest Protestant denomination in the United States and has been a vocal critic of gay marriage and abortion rights .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "Southern Baptist Convention", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 31, "obj": "Protestant", "obj_start": 47, "obj_end": 57, "relation": "org:political/religious_affiliation"}
{"text": "The Jewish Community Center of Greater Pittsburgh is a non-profit organization that provides cultural, recreational, and educational programs for the Jewish community .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "Jewish Community Center of Greater Pittsburgh", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 49, "obj": "Jewish", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 10, "relation": "org:political/religious_affiliation"}
{"text": "The Catholic Church has been involved in numerous scandals involving sexual abuse of children by priests and cover-ups by church officials .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "Catholic Church", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 19, "obj": "Catholic", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 12, "relation": "org:political/religious_affiliation"}
{"text": "The Presbyterian Church (USA) has been a vocal advocate for social justice issues such as poverty, hunger, and immigration reform .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "Presbyterian Church (USA)", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 29, "obj": "Presbyterian", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 16, "relation": "org:political/religious_affiliation"}
{"text": "The United Methodist Church has been a strong supporter of immigration reform and has called for a more compassionate and inclusive approach to the issue .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "United Methodist Church", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 27, "obj": "Methodist", "obj_start": 11, "obj_end": 20, "relation": "org:political/religious_affiliation"}
{"text": "The Quakers have been a vocal critic of the Iraq war and have called for a more peaceful approach to conflict resolution .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "Quakers", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "Quaker", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 10, "relation": "org:political/religious_affiliation"}
{"text": "The company 's board of directors voted to dissolve the company in 2018 due to financial difficulties .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "2018", "obj_start": 67, "obj_end": 71, "relation": "org:dissolved"}
{"text": "The partnership between the two companies was dissolved in 2012 due to creative differences .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "two companies", "subj_start": 28, "subj_end": 41, "obj": "2012", "obj_start": 59, "obj_end": 63, "relation": "org:dissolved"}
{"text": "The merger between the two banks was dissolved in 2001 due to regulatory issues .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "two banks", "subj_start": 23, "subj_end": 32, "obj": "2001", "obj_start": 50, "obj_end": 54, "relation": "org:dissolved"}
{"text": "The joint venture between the two companies was dissolved in 2015 due to disagreements over the direction of the project .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "two companies", "subj_start": 30, "subj_end": 43, "obj": "2015", "obj_start": 61, "obj_end": 65, "relation": "org:dissolved"}
{"text": "The company 's subsidiary was dissolved in 2010 due to financial difficulties .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "2010", "obj_start": 43, "obj_end": 47, "relation": "org:dissolved"}
{"text": "The partnership between the two artists was dissolved in 2017 due to creative differences .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "two artists", "subj_start": 28, "subj_end": 39, "obj": "2017", "obj_start": 57, "obj_end": 61, "relation": "org:dissolved"}
{"text": "The non-profit organization was dissolved in 2014 due to lack of funding .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "non-profit organization", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 27, "obj": "2014", "obj_start": 45, "obj_end": 49, "relation": "org:dissolved"}
{"text": "The government agency was dissolved in 2016 due to a reorganization of the government 's structure .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "government agency", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 21, "obj": "2016", "obj_start": 39, "obj_end": 43, "relation": "org:dissolved"}
{"text": "The actor married his wife , actress Sarah Jessica Parker , in 1997 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "actor", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 9, "obj": "Sarah Jessica Parker", "obj_start": 37, "obj_end": 57, "relation": "per:spouse"}
{"text": "The singer married her husband , music producer David Foster , in 2010 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "singer", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 10, "obj": "David Foster", "obj_start": 48, "obj_end": 60, "relation": "per:spouse"}
{"text": "The politician married his wife , a former Miss America , in 1988 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "politician", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 14, "obj": "Miss America", "obj_start": 43, "obj_end": 55, "relation": "per:spouse"}
{"text": "The actress married her husband , a businessman , in 2012 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "actress", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "businessman", "obj_start": 36, "obj_end": 47, "relation": "per:spouse"}
{"text": "The musician married his wife , a model , in 2008 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "musician", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 12, "obj": "model", "obj_start": 34, "obj_end": 39, "relation": "per:spouse"}
{"text": "The athlete married his wife , a former Olympic gold medalist , in 2014 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "athlete", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "former Olympic gold medalist", "obj_start": 33, "obj_end": 61, "relation": "per:spouse"}
{"text": "35-year-old Maria Sharapova is a Russian professional tennis player who has won 32 WTA titles and four Grand Slam singles titles .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DURATION", "subj": "Maria Sharapova", "subj_start": 12, "subj_end": 27, "obj": "35-year-old", "obj_start": 0, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:age"}
{"text": "27-year-old Prince William is second in line to the British throne and is married to Catherine, Duchess of Cambridge .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DURATION", "subj": "Prince William", "subj_start": 12, "subj_end": 26, "obj": "27-year-old", "obj_start": 0, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:age"}
{"text": "45-year-old Leonardo DiCaprio is an American actor and producer who has starred in many successful movies such as Titanic and The Wolf of Wall Street .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DURATION", "subj": "Leonardo DiCaprio", "subj_start": 12, "subj_end": 29, "obj": "45-year-old", "obj_start": 0, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:age"}
{"text": "82-year-old Nelson Mandela was the first black president of South Africa and a anti-apartheid revolutionary .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "Nelson Mandela", "subj_start": 12, "subj_end": 26, "obj": "82-year-old", "obj_start": 0, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:age"}
{"text": "31-year-old Taylor Swift is an American singer-songwriter who has won many awards for her music .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DURATION", "subj": "Taylor Swift", "subj_start": 12, "subj_end": 24, "obj": "31-year-old", "obj_start": 0, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:age"}
{"text": "41-year-old Jennifer Lopez is an American actress, singer, and dancer who has starred in many successful movies and music albums .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DURATION", "subj": "Jennifer Lopez", "subj_start": 12, "subj_end": 26, "obj": "41-year-old", "obj_start": 0, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:age"}
{"text": "* The conference will be held in Chicago , Illinois .", "subj_type": "LOCATION", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Chicago", "subj_start": 33, "subj_end": 40, "obj": "Illinois", "obj_start": 43, "obj_end": 51, "relation": "per:stateorprovinces_of_residence"}
{"text": "The Nobel Peace Prize winner and former leader of the Soviet Union , Mikhail Gorbachev , was born in the village of Privolnoye in Stavropol Krai , Russia .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Mikhail Gorbachev", "subj_start": 69, "subj_end": 86, "obj": "Russia", "obj_start": 147, "obj_end": 153, "relation": "per:country_of_birth"}
{"text": "The founder of Microsoft , Bill Gates , was born in Seattle , Washington , U.S.A. .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Bill Gates", "subj_start": 27, "subj_end": 37, "obj": "U.S.", "obj_start": 75, "obj_end": 79, "relation": "per:country_of_birth"}
{"text": "The famous physicist Albert Einstein was born in the Kingdom of Württemberg , which is now part of Germany .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Albert Einstein", "subj_start": 21, "subj_end": 36, "obj": "Germany", "obj_start": 99, "obj_end": 106, "relation": "per:country_of_birth"}
{"text": "The actress and model Pamela Anderson was born in Ladysmith , British Columbia , Canada .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Pamela Anderson", "subj_start": 22, "subj_end": 37, "obj": "Canada", "obj_start": 81, "obj_end": 87, "relation": "per:country_of_birth"}
{"text": "The singer and songwriter Bob Dylan was born Robert Allen Zimmerman in Duluth , Minnesota , U.S.A. .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Bob Dylan", "subj_start": 26, "subj_end": 35, "obj": "U.S.", "obj_start": 92, "obj_end": 96, "relation": "per:country_of_birth"}
{"text": "The former U.S. President George H.W. Bush was born in Milton , Massachusetts , U.S.A. .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "George H.W. Bush", "subj_start": 26, "subj_end": 42, "obj": "U.S.", "obj_start": 11, "obj_end": 15, "relation": "per:country_of_birth"}
{"text": "The famous painter Vincent van Gogh was born in Groot-Zundert , Netherlands .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Vincent van Gogh", "subj_start": 19, "subj_end": 35, "obj": "Netherlands", "obj_start": 64, "obj_end": 75, "relation": "per:country_of_birth"}
{"text": "The former British Prime Minister Tony Blair was born in Edinburgh , Scotland , U.K. .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Tony Blair", "subj_start": 34, "subj_end": 44, "obj": "U.K.", "obj_start": 80, "obj_end": 84, "relation": "per:country_of_birth"}
{"text": "The United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) has expressed concern over the situation of Rohingya refugees in Bangladesh , who are facing a range of challenges including overcrowding , poor sanitation and limited access to healthcare .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "UNHCR", "subj_start": 51, "subj_end": 56, "obj": "Bangladesh", "obj_start": 123, "obj_end": 133, "relation": "per:countries_of_residence"}
{"text": "The World Health Organization (WHO) has declared the outbreak of Ebola in the Democratic Republic of Congo a global health emergency , with the virus spreading to Uganda and Rwanda .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "WHO", "subj_start": 31, "subj_end": 34, "obj": "Democratic Republic of Congo", "obj_start": 78, "obj_end": 106, "relation": "per:countries_of_residence"}
{"text": "The United States has imposed sanctions on several Russian officials and businesses over the annexation of Crimea , including the head of the Federal Security Service (FSB) Alexander Bortnikov .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Alexander Bortnikov", "subj_start": 173, "subj_end": 192, "obj": "Russia", "obj_start": 51, "obj_end": 57, "relation": "per:countries_of_residence"}
{"text": "The European Union has threatened to impose sanctions on the government of Hungary over its controversial migration policies , which the EU says violate the rule of law and human rights .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "European Union", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 18, "obj": "Hungary", "obj_start": 75, "obj_end": 82, "relation": "per:countries_of_residence"}
{"text": "The United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) has warned that the ongoing conflict in Yemen has left millions of children at risk of malnutrition , disease and death , with over 1000000 children suffering from acute malnutrition .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "UNICEF", "subj_start": 36, "subj_end": 42, "obj": "Yemen", "obj_start": 84, "obj_end": 89, "relation": "per:countries_of_residence"}
{"text": "The World Trade Organization (WTO) has ruled in favor of the United States in a dispute with China over tariffs on imported steel , with the WTO finding that China's measures were inconsistent with its obligations under the WTO agreements .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "WTO", "subj_start": 30, "subj_end": 33, "obj": "China", "obj_start": 93, "obj_end": 98, "relation": "per:countries_of_residence"}
{"text": "The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has approved a $ 12 billion loan package for Argentina to help the country recover from a deep economic crisis , with the IMF praising the government's economic reform plan .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "IMF", "subj_start": 33, "subj_end": 36, "obj": "Argentina", "obj_start": 83, "obj_end": 92, "relation": "per:countries_of_residence"}
{"text": "She is survived by her sisters , Mary and Jane , and her brother , John .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Mary", "subj_start": 33, "subj_end": 37, "obj": "Jane", "obj_start": 42, "obj_end": 46, "relation": "per:siblings"}
{"text": "The two brothers , John and Michael , are both lawyers .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "John", "subj_start": 19, "subj_end": 23, "obj": "Michael", "obj_start": 28, "obj_end": 35, "relation": "per:siblings"}
{"text": "The family includes her husband , John , and their three children , Emily , Sarah , and Benjamin .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Emily", "subj_start": 68, "subj_end": 73, "obj": "Benjamin", "obj_start": 88, "obj_end": 96, "relation": "per:siblings"}
{"text": "Her sisters , Rachel and Leah , are both doctors .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Rachel", "subj_start": 14, "subj_end": 20, "obj": "Leah", "obj_start": 25, "obj_end": 29, "relation": "per:siblings"}
{"text": "The two brothers , William and Robert , are both actors .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "William", "subj_start": 19, "subj_end": 26, "obj": "Robert", "obj_start": 31, "obj_end": 37, "relation": "per:siblings"}
{"text": "The family includes her parents , John and Mary , and her brother , James .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "John", "subj_start": 34, "subj_end": 38, "obj": "James", "obj_start": 68, "obj_end": 73, "relation": "per:siblings"}
{"text": "Her sisters , Elizabeth and Catherine , are both lawyers .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Elizabeth", "subj_start": 14, "subj_end": 23, "obj": "Catherine", "obj_start": 28, "obj_end": 37, "relation": "per:siblings"}
{"text": "The two brothers , Peter and Paul , are both musicians .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Peter", "subj_start": 19, "subj_end": 24, "obj": "Paul", "obj_start": 29, "obj_end": 33, "relation": "per:siblings"}
{"text": "Before his election to Congress , Obama worked as a community organizer and civil rights attorney in Chicago .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Obama", "subj_start": 34, "subj_end": 39, "obj": "Congress", "obj_start": 23, "obj_end": 31, "relation": "per:employee_of"}
{"text": "The company 's CEO , John Doe , has been with the company for over 20 years and has seen it grow from a small startup to a global leader in the industry .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "John Doe", "subj_start": 21, "subj_end": 29, "obj": "company", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:employee_of"}
{"text": "The new policy will affect all employees of the company , regardless of their location or job function .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 48, "subj_end": 55, "obj": "employees", "obj_start": 31, "obj_end": 40, "relation": "per:employee_of"}
{"text": "The city 's mayor , Jane Smith , has been a vocal advocate for education reform and has worked tirelessly to improve the city 's schools .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Jane Smith", "subj_start": 20, "subj_end": 30, "obj": "city", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 8, "relation": "per:employee_of"}
{"text": "The company 's CFO , Mary Johnson , has extensive experience in financial management and has played a key role in the company 's success .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Mary Johnson", "subj_start": 21, "subj_end": 33, "obj": "company", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:employee_of"}
{"text": "The team 's coach , John Smith , has been instrumental in the team 's success and has a reputation for being one of the best coaches in the league .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "John Smith", "subj_start": 20, "subj_end": 30, "obj": "team", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 8, "relation": "per:employee_of"}
{"text": "The university 's president , Dr. Jane Doe , has been a driving force behind the university 's growth and success .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Dr. Jane Doe", "subj_start": 30, "subj_end": 42, "obj": "university", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 14, "relation": "per:employee_of"}
{"text": "The company 's founder , Bob Smith , has a long history of innovation and has been recognized as one of the industry 's leading visionaries .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Bob Smith", "subj_start": 25, "subj_end": 34, "obj": "company", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:employee_of"}
{"text": "2019-04-15T13:40:00Z The company was charged with tax evasion and fraud .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "CRIMINAL_CHARGE", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 25, "subj_end": 32, "obj": "tax evasion", "obj_start": 50, "obj_end": 61, "relation": "per:charges"}
{"text": "Actor Tom Sizemore pleaded no contest to domestic violence and was sentenced to 17 months in prison .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CRIMINAL_CHARGE", "subj": "Tom Sizemore", "subj_start": 6, "subj_end": 18, "obj": "domestic violence", "obj_start": 41, "obj_end": 58, "relation": "per:charges"}
{"text": "The former CEO of Theranos, Elizabeth Holmes, was charged with wire fraud and conspiracy to commit wire fraud .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CRIMINAL_CHARGE", "subj": "Elizabeth Holmes", "subj_start": 28, "subj_end": 44, "obj": "wire fraud", "obj_start": 63, "obj_end": 73, "relation": "per:charges"}
{"text": "The music producer, Dr. Luke, was sued by Kesha for sexual assault and battery .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CRIMINAL_CHARGE", "subj": "Dr. Luke", "subj_start": 20, "subj_end": 28, "obj": "sexual assault", "obj_start": 52, "obj_end": 66, "relation": "per:charges"}
{"text": "The actor, Kevin Spacey, was charged with sexual assault .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CRIMINAL_CHARGE", "subj": "Kevin Spacey", "subj_start": 11, "subj_end": 23, "obj": "sexual assault", "obj_start": 42, "obj_end": 56, "relation": "per:charges"}
{"text": "The company, Uber, was charged with criminal mischief and reckless endangerment .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "CRIMINAL_CHARGE", "subj": "Uber", "subj_start": 13, "subj_end": 17, "obj": "criminal mischief", "obj_start": 36, "obj_end": 53, "relation": "per:charges"}
{"text": "The former FIFA vice president, Jeffrey Webb, was charged with racketeering, wire fraud, and money laundering .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CRIMINAL_CHARGE", "subj": "Jeffrey Webb", "subj_start": 32, "subj_end": 44, "obj": "racketeering", "obj_start": 63, "obj_end": 75, "relation": "per:charges"}
{"text": "The pharmaceutical company, Purdue Pharma, was charged with conspiracy to defraud the United States and violating federal anti-kickback laws .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "CRIMINAL_CHARGE", "subj": "Purdue Pharma", "subj_start": 28, "subj_end": 41, "obj": "conspiracy", "obj_start": 60, "obj_end": 70, "relation": "per:charges"}
{"text": "He graduated from Yale Law School in 1995 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "He", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 2, "obj": "Yale Law School", "obj_start": 18, "obj_end": 33, "relation": "per:schools_attended"}
{"text": "After completing his undergraduate degree at the University of Michigan , he went on to earn his MBA from Harvard Business School .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "he", "subj_start": 46, "subj_end": 48, "obj": "Harvard Business School", "obj_start": 106, "obj_end": 129, "relation": "per:schools_attended"}
{"text": "He studied at Oxford University as a Rhodes Scholar and received a degree in philosophy, politics, and economics .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "He", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 2, "obj": "Oxford University", "obj_start": 14, "obj_end": 31, "relation": "per:schools_attended"}
{"text": "She earned her undergraduate degree in computer science from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in 2010 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "She", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 3, "obj": "Massachusetts Institute of Technology", "obj_start": 65, "obj_end": 102, "relation": "per:schools_attended"}
{"text": "He received his medical degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 2002 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "He", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 2, "obj": "University of Pennsylvania", "obj_start": 40, "obj_end": 66, "relation": "per:schools_attended"}
{"text": "She studied at the University of California , San Diego and received a degree in biology .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "She", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 3, "obj": "University of California , San Diego", "obj_start": 19, "obj_end": 55, "relation": "per:schools_attended"}
{"text": "The Japanese electronics giant Sony has announced that it will acquire the remaining shares of Sony Ericsson from its partner Ericsson for $1.5 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Sony", "subj_start": 31, "subj_end": 35, "obj": "Ericsson", "obj_start": 100, "obj_end": 108, "relation": "org:parents"}
{"text": "The US-based online retailer Amazon has acquired the online payment service provider PayPal for $1.3 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Amazon", "subj_start": 29, "subj_end": 35, "obj": "PayPal", "obj_start": 85, "obj_end": 91, "relation": "org:parents"}
{"text": "The French automaker Renault has announced that it will acquire a 25% stake in the Japanese automaker Nissan for $2.8 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Renault", "subj_start": 21, "subj_end": 28, "obj": "Nissan", "obj_start": 102, "obj_end": 108, "relation": "org:parents"}
{"text": "The UK-based pharmaceutical company GlaxoSmithKline has acquired the US-based biotech company Human Genome Sciences for $3.9 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "GlaxoSmithKline", "subj_start": 36, "subj_end": 51, "obj": "Human Genome Sciences", "obj_start": 94, "obj_end": 115, "relation": "org:parents"}
{"text": "The Chinese e-commerce giant Alibaba has acquired the online retailer VIPShop for $2.6 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Alibaba", "subj_start": 29, "subj_end": 36, "obj": "VIPShop", "obj_start": 70, "obj_end": 77, "relation": "org:parents"}
{"text": "The US-based software company Microsoft has acquired the online advertising company aQuantive for $6.2 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Microsoft", "subj_start": 30, "subj_end": 39, "obj": "aQuantive", "obj_start": 84, "obj_end": 93, "relation": "org:parents"}
{"text": "The Japanese electronics giant Panasonic has acquired the US-based solar panel manufacturer SolarWorld for $2.5 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Panasonic", "subj_start": 31, "subj_end": 40, "obj": "SolarWorld", "obj_start": 92, "obj_end": 102, "relation": "org:parents"}
{"text": "The UK-based bank Barclays has acquired the US-based investment bank Lehman Brothers for $2.3 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Barclays", "subj_start": 18, "subj_end": 26, "obj": "Lehman Brothers", "obj_start": 69, "obj_end": 84, "relation": "org:parents"}
{"text": "Hickenlooper was born in Narberth , Pennsylvania , on February 7 , 1952 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Hickenlooper", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 12, "obj": "Pennsylvania", "obj_start": 36, "obj_end": 48, "relation": "per:stateorprovince_of_birth"}
{"text": "Klobuchar was born in Plymouth , Minnesota , on May 25 , 1960 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Klobuchar", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 9, "obj": "Minnesota", "obj_start": 33, "obj_end": 42, "relation": "per:stateorprovince_of_birth"}
{"text": "Booker was born in Washington , D. C. , on December 27 , 1969 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Booker", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 6, "obj": "Washington", "obj_start": 19, "obj_end": 29, "relation": "per:stateorprovince_of_birth"}
{"text": "Gillibrand was born in Albany , New York , on December 9 , 1966 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Gillibrand", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 10, "obj": "New York", "obj_start": 32, "obj_end": 40, "relation": "per:stateorprovince_of_birth"}
{"text": "Brown was born in Des Moines , Iowa , on December 19 , 1959 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Brown", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 5, "obj": "Iowa", "obj_start": 31, "obj_end": 35, "relation": "per:stateorprovince_of_birth"}
{"text": "Sanders was born in Brooklyn , New York , on September 8 , 1941 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Sanders", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 7, "obj": "New York", "obj_start": 31, "obj_end": 39, "relation": "per:stateorprovince_of_birth"}
{"text": "Warren was born in Oklahoma City , Oklahoma , on June 22 , 1958 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Warren", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 6, "obj": "Oklahoma", "obj_start": 19, "obj_end": 27, "relation": "per:stateorprovince_of_birth"}
{"text": "Cotton was born in Houston , Texas , on May 13 , 1977 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Cotton", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 6, "obj": "Texas", "obj_start": 29, "obj_end": 34, "relation": "per:stateorprovince_of_birth"}
{"text": "The Basotho Congress Party (BCP) was founded by Mosisili in 1997 as a breakaway faction of the Basotho National Party (BNP) .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Basotho Congress Party", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 26, "obj": "Mosisili", "obj_start": 48, "obj_end": 56, "relation": "org:founded_by"}
{"text": "The Lesotho Workers Party (LWP) was founded by Thabane in 1980 as a left-wing political party .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Lesotho Workers Party", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 25, "obj": "Thabane", "obj_start": 47, "obj_end": 54, "relation": "org:founded_by"}
{"text": "The Basotho Youth Congress (BYC) was founded by Mokhothu in 2000 as a youth wing of the Basotho National Party (BNP) .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Basotho Youth Congress", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 26, "obj": "Mokhothu", "obj_start": 48, "obj_end": 56, "relation": "org:founded_by"}
{"text": "The All Basotho Students Union (ABSU) was founded by Mokhothu in 1995 as a student organization .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "All Basotho Students Union", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 30, "obj": "Mokhothu", "obj_start": 53, "obj_end": 61, "relation": "org:founded_by"}
{"text": "The Lesotho Women 's Federation (LWF) was founded by Mokhothu in 1990 as a women 's rights organization .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Lesotho Women 's Federation", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 31, "obj": "Mokhothu", "obj_start": 53, "obj_end": 61, "relation": "org:founded_by"}
{"text": "The Basotho National Party (BNP) was founded by Mosisili in 1980 as a political party .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Basotho National Party", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 26, "obj": "Mosisili", "obj_start": 48, "obj_end": 56, "relation": "org:founded_by"}
{"text": "The Lesotho Congress for Democracy (LCD) was founded by Thabane in 1998 as a coalition of political parties .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Lesotho Congress for Democracy", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 34, "obj": "Thabane", "obj_start": 56, "obj_end": 63, "relation": "org:founded_by"}
{"text": "The Basotho People 's Congress (BPC) was founded by Mokhothu in 2005 as a political party .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Basotho People 's Congress", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 30, "obj": "Mokhothu", "obj_start": 52, "obj_end": 60, "relation": "org:founded_by"}
{"text": "The company has over 10,000 employees worldwide .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "10,000", "obj_start": 21, "obj_end": 27, "relation": "org:number_of_employees/members"}
{"text": "The organization has a staff of 500 people .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "organization", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 16, "obj": "500", "obj_start": 32, "obj_end": 35, "relation": "org:number_of_employees/members"}
{"text": "The company has 20,000 employees in the United States .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "20,000", "obj_start": 16, "obj_end": 22, "relation": "org:number_of_employees/members"}
{"text": "The university has a student body of over 40,000 students .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "university", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 14, "obj": "40,000", "obj_start": 42, "obj_end": 48, "relation": "org:number_of_employees/members"}
{"text": "The company has 15,000 employees in Europe .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "15,000", "obj_start": 16, "obj_end": 22, "relation": "org:number_of_employees/members"}
{"text": "The organization has 3,000 members worldwide .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "organization", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 16, "obj": "3,000", "obj_start": 21, "obj_end": 26, "relation": "org:number_of_employees/members"}
{"text": "The company has 25,000 employees in Asia .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "company", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "25,000", "obj_start": 16, "obj_end": 22, "relation": "org:number_of_employees/members"}
{"text": "The organization has 10,000 members in the United States .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "NUMBER", "subj": "organization", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 16, "obj": "10,000", "obj_start": 21, "obj_end": 27, "relation": "org:number_of_employees/members"}
{"text": "The corporation has its headquarters in Houston , Texas .", "subj_type": "CITY", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Houston", "subj_start": 40, "subj_end": 47, "obj": "Texas", "obj_start": 50, "obj_end": 55, "relation": "org:stateorprovince_of_headquarters"}
{"text": "The company has its headquarters in Chicago , Illinois .", "subj_type": "CITY", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Chicago", "subj_start": 36, "subj_end": 43, "obj": "Illinois", "obj_start": 46, "obj_end": 54, "relation": "org:stateorprovince_of_headquarters"}
{"text": "The organization is based in Phoenix , Arizona .", "subj_type": "CITY", "obj_type": "STATE_OR_PROVINCE", "subj": "Phoenix", "subj_start": 29, "subj_end": 36, "obj": "Arizona", "obj_start": 39, "obj_end": 46, "relation": "org:stateorprovince_of_headquarters"}
{"text": "The 2008 Summer Olympics in Beijing , China , were the first Olympics to be held in China , and they were also the largest and most expensive Olympics in history .", "subj_type": "LOCATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Beijing", "subj_start": 28, "subj_end": 35, "obj": "China", "obj_start": 38, "obj_end": 43, "relation": "per:origin"}
{"text": "The 1984 Bhopal disaster was a catastrophic chemical leak that occurred at a Union Carbide pesticide plant in Bhopal , India , and it caused widespread death and injury and environmental damage .", "subj_type": "LOCATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Bhopal", "subj_start": 9, "subj_end": 15, "obj": "India", "obj_start": 119, "obj_end": 124, "relation": "per:origin"}
{"text": "The 1992 Los Angeles riots were sparked by the acquittal of four white police officers who had been videotaped beating a black motorist , Rodney King , and they resulted in widespread property damage , looting , and violence .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "LOCATION", "subj": "Rodney King", "subj_start": 138, "subj_end": 149, "obj": "Los Angeles", "obj_start": 9, "obj_end": 20, "relation": "per:origin"}
{"text": "The 2004 Indian Ocean tsunami was a massive wave that was triggered by a 9.1-magnitude earthquake off the coast of Indonesia , and it caused widespread destruction and loss of life in several countries in Southeast Asia and Africa .", "subj_type": "LOCATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Indian Ocean", "subj_start": 9, "subj_end": 21, "obj": "Indonesia", "obj_start": 115, "obj_end": 124, "relation": "per:origin"}
{"text": "The renowned physicist , who died last week at 87 , was known for his groundbreaking research on black holes .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The renowned physicist", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 22, "obj": "last week", "obj_start": 34, "obj_end": 43, "relation": "per:date_of_death"}
{"text": "The legendary actress , who passed away last month at 95 , was best known for her iconic roles in classic films .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The legendary actress", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 21, "obj": "last month", "obj_start": 40, "obj_end": 50, "relation": "per:date_of_death"}
{"text": "The celebrated author , who died last year at 75 , was known for his bestselling novels and Pulitzer Prize wins .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The celebrated author", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 21, "obj": "last year", "obj_start": 33, "obj_end": 42, "relation": "per:date_of_death"}
{"text": "The pioneering computer scientist , who passed away last week at 83 , was a pioneer in the field of artificial intelligence .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The pioneering computer scientist", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 33, "obj": "last week", "obj_start": 52, "obj_end": 61, "relation": "per:date_of_death"}
{"text": "The influential artist , who died last month at 88 , was known for his bold and innovative style .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The influential artist", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 22, "obj": "last month", "obj_start": 34, "obj_end": 44, "relation": "per:date_of_death"}
{"text": "The respected historian , who passed away last year at 92 , was an expert on ancient civilizations .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The respected historian", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 23, "obj": "last year", "obj_start": 42, "obj_end": 51, "relation": "per:date_of_death"}
{"text": "The celebrated musician , who died last week at 76 , was known for his iconic songs and powerful voice .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The celebrated musician", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 23, "obj": "last week", "obj_start": 35, "obj_end": 44, "relation": "per:date_of_death"}
{"text": "The renowned scientist , who passed away last month at 84 , was a leading expert in the field of cancer research .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The renowned scientist", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 22, "obj": "last month", "obj_start": 41, "obj_end": 51, "relation": "per:date_of_death"}
{"text": "The World Health Organization (WHO) has declared that the COVID-19 outbreak in the United States is under control .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "World Health Organization", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 29, "obj": "United States", "obj_start": 83, "obj_end": 96, "relation": "org:country_of_headquarters"}
{"text": "The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has approved a loan of $12 billion to help Greece recover from its financial crisis .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "IMF", "subj_start": 33, "subj_end": 36, "obj": "Greece", "obj_start": 81, "obj_end": 87, "relation": "org:country_of_headquarters"}
{"text": "The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) has expressed concern over Iran's nuclear program and has called for greater transparency .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "IAEA", "subj_start": 40, "subj_end": 44, "obj": "Iran", "obj_start": 73, "obj_end": 77, "relation": "org:country_of_headquarters"}
{"text": "The World Bank has approved a loan of $500 million to help India improve its power grid .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "World Bank", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 14, "obj": "India", "obj_start": 59, "obj_end": 64, "relation": "org:country_of_headquarters"}
{"text": "The American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) is a member of the Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights , which is a coalition of more than 200 national organizations committed to promoting and protecting the civil and human rights of all individuals .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "American Civil Liberties Union", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 34, "obj": "Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights", "obj_start": 61, "obj_end": 108, "relation": "org:member_of"}
{"text": "The World Wildlife Fund (WWF) is a member of the Global Environment Facility (GEF) , which is an international partnership of governments, civil society organizations, and the private sector that aims to address global environmental issues .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "World Wildlife Fund", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 23, "obj": "Global Environment Facility", "obj_start": 49, "obj_end": 76, "relation": "org:member_of"}
{"text": "The United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) is a member of the United Nations Development Group (UNDG) , which is a coalition of 32 UN agencies and programs that work together to support sustainable development and eradicate poverty .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "United Nations Children's Fund", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 34, "obj": "United Nations Development Group", "obj_start": 63, "obj_end": 95, "relation": "org:member_of"}
{"text": "The International Olympic Committee (IOC) is a member of the Association of National Olympic Committees (ANOC) , which is a non-profit organization that represents all 206 National Olympic Committees and acts as a liaison between the NOCs and the IOC .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "International Olympic Committee", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 35, "obj": "Association of National Olympic Committees", "obj_start": 61, "obj_end": 103, "relation": "org:member_of"}
{"text": "The World Health Organization (WHO) is a member of the United Nations System , which is a collective of specialized agencies that work together to achieve the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "World Health Organization", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 29, "obj": "United Nations System", "obj_start": 55, "obj_end": 76, "relation": "org:member_of"}
{"text": "The World Wildlife Fund (WWF) is a member of the Global Environment Facility (GEF) , which is an international partnership of governments, civil society organizations, and the private sector that aims to address global environmental issues .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "World Wildlife Fund", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 23, "obj": "Global Environment Facility", "obj_start": 49, "obj_end": 76, "relation": "org:member_of"}
{"text": "Pope Francis , the first Jesuit pope , has called for a more inclusive and compassionate Catholic Church .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "Pope Francis", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 12, "obj": "Catholic", "obj_start": 89, "obj_end": 97, "relation": "per:religion"}
{"text": "The Ayatollah Khomeini has been a key figure in promoting the Islamic Revolution in Iran and has called for a more inclusive and compassionate Islamic society .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "RELIGION", "subj": "Ayatollah Khomeini", "subj_start": 4, "subj_end": 22, "obj": "Islam", "obj_start": 62, "obj_end": 67, "relation": "per:religion"}
{"text": "The European Union ( EU ) has imposed sanctions on several Iranian officials and entities , including the Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps ( IRGC ) , over the country's nuclear program .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "IRGC", "subj_start": 142, "subj_end": 146, "obj": "European Union", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 18, "relation": "org:alternate_names"}
{"text": "The International Criminal Court ( ICC ) has issued an arrest warrant for Sudanese President Omar al-Bashir for war crimes and crimes against humanity committed in Darfur .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "ICC", "subj_start": 35, "subj_end": 38, "obj": "Sudan", "obj_start": 74, "obj_end": 79, "relation": "org:alternate_names"}
{"text": "The United Nations Children's Fund ( UNICEF ) has appealed for $2.3 billion in funding to support children affected by the conflict in Yemen .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "UNICEF", "subj_start": 37, "subj_end": 43, "obj": "Yemen", "obj_start": 135, "obj_end": 140, "relation": "org:alternate_names"}
{"text": "The International Monetary Fund ( IMF ) has approved a $12 billion loan package for Argentina to help the country recover from its economic crisis .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "IMF", "subj_start": 34, "subj_end": 37, "obj": "Argentina", "obj_start": 84, "obj_end": 93, "relation": "org:alternate_names"}
{"text": "The International Atomic Energy Agency ( IAEA ) has expressed concern over Iran's plans to increase its uranium enrichment levels beyond the limits set by the 2015 nuclear deal .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "IAEA", "subj_start": 41, "subj_end": 45, "obj": "Iran", "obj_start": 75, "obj_end": 79, "relation": "org:alternate_names"}
{"text": "Former Cuban leader Fidel Castro 's brother dies at 88", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Fidel Castro", "subj_start": 20, "subj_end": 32, "obj": "Cuba", "obj_start": 7, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:country_of_death"}
{"text": "U.S. Rep. John Lewis , civil rights icon , dies at 80", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "John Lewis", "subj_start": 10, "subj_end": 20, "obj": "U.S.", "obj_start": 0, "obj_end": 4, "relation": "per:country_of_death"}
{"text": "Former Indian leader Indira Gandhi 's mother dies at 92", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Indira Gandhi", "subj_start": 21, "subj_end": 34, "obj": "India", "obj_start": 7, "obj_end": 12, "relation": "per:country_of_death"}
{"text": "Former Pakistani leader Benazir Bhutto 's father dies at 82", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Benazir Bhutto", "subj_start": 24, "subj_end": 38, "obj": "Pakistan", "obj_start": 7, "obj_end": 15, "relation": "per:country_of_death"}
{"text": "Former Iranian leader Ayatollah Khomeini 's mother dies at 95", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Ayatollah Khomeini", "subj_start": 22, "subj_end": 40, "obj": "Iran", "obj_start": 7, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:country_of_death"}
{"text": "U.S. Rep. Elijah Cummings , civil rights leader , dies at 68", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Elijah Cummings", "subj_start": 10, "subj_end": 25, "obj": "U.S.", "obj_start": 0, "obj_end": 4, "relation": "per:country_of_death"}
{"text": "The Spanish company Repsol YPF said it would sell a 4.9% stake in the company to the Qatari sovereign wealth fund for $ 2.9 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Repsol YPF", "subj_start": 20, "subj_end": 30, "obj": "Qatari sovereign wealth fund", "obj_start": 85, "obj_end": 113, "relation": "org:shareholders"}
{"text": "The private equity firm KKR & Co LP said it would acquire a majority stake in the Chinese snack food maker Jingdong Cereal Co for $ 1.2 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Jingdong Cereal Co", "subj_start": 107, "subj_end": 125, "obj": "KKR & Co LP", "obj_start": 24, "obj_end": 35, "relation": "org:shareholders"}
{"text": "The Japanese electronics company Sony Corp said it would sell its stake in the video game maker Bungie Inc to the private equity firm Haven Capital for $ 100 million .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Bungie Inc", "subj_start": 96, "subj_end": 106, "obj": "Sony Corp", "obj_start": 33, "obj_end": 42, "relation": "org:shareholders"}
{"text": "The French luxury goods maker Kering SA said it would acquire a 49% stake in the Italian fashion house Bottega Veneta for $ 2.5 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Bottega Veneta", "subj_start": 103, "subj_end": 117, "obj": "Kering SA", "obj_start": 30, "obj_end": 39, "relation": "org:shareholders"}
{"text": "The US media company Comcast Corp said it would acquire a 51% stake in the British broadcaster Sky plc for $ 30 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Sky plc", "subj_start": 95, "subj_end": 102, "obj": "Comcast Corp", "obj_start": 21, "obj_end": 33, "relation": "org:shareholders"}
{"text": "The Chinese e-commerce company Alibaba Group Holding Ltd said it would acquire a 33% stake in the logistics company Cainiao Network Technology Co for $ 2.9 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Cainiao Network Technology Co", "subj_start": 116, "subj_end": 145, "obj": "Alibaba Group Holding Ltd", "obj_start": 31, "obj_end": 56, "relation": "org:shareholders"}
{"text": "The US private equity firm Blackstone Group LP said it would acquire a majority stake in the Indian IT services company Hexaware Technologies Ltd for $ 1.2 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Hexaware Technologies Ltd", "subj_start": 120, "subj_end": 145, "obj": "Blackstone Group LP", "obj_start": 27, "obj_end": 46, "relation": "org:shareholders"}
{"text": "The Japanese telecommunications company SoftBank Corp said it would sell a 4.9% stake in the company to the Saudi sovereign wealth fund for $ 2.9 billion .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "SoftBank Corp", "subj_start": 40, "subj_end": 53, "obj": "Saudi sovereign wealth fund", "obj_start": 108, "obj_end": 135, "relation": "org:shareholders"}
{"text": "She is survived by her husband of 40 years , John Smith ; two daughters , Jane and Mary ; and a son , Bob .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Jane", "subj_start": 74, "subj_end": 78, "obj": "Mary", "obj_start": 83, "obj_end": 87, "relation": "per:children"}
{"text": "He is survived by his wife of 30 years , Sarah Johnson ; two sons , Tom and Alex ; and a daughter , Emily .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Tom", "subj_start": 68, "subj_end": 71, "obj": "Emily", "obj_start": 100, "obj_end": 105, "relation": "per:children"}
{"text": "She is survived by her husband of 25 years , Mark Davis ; two daughters , Lily and Rose ; and a son , Jack .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Lily", "subj_start": 74, "subj_end": 78, "obj": "Rose", "obj_start": 83, "obj_end": 87, "relation": "per:children"}
{"text": "He is survived by his wife of 15 years , Lisa Brown ; a daughter , Samantha ; and two sons , James and William .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Samantha", "subj_start": 67, "subj_end": 75, "obj": "William", "obj_start": 103, "obj_end": 110, "relation": "per:children"}
{"text": "She is survived by her husband of 45 years , Robert Green ; two daughters , Rachel and Rebecca ; and a son , Benjamin .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Rachel", "subj_start": 76, "subj_end": 82, "obj": "Rebecca", "obj_start": 87, "obj_end": 94, "relation": "per:children"}
{"text": "He is survived by his wife of 35 years , Margaret Lee ; two sons , David and Michael ; and a daughter , Elizabeth .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "David", "subj_start": 67, "subj_end": 72, "obj": "Elizabeth", "obj_start": 104, "obj_end": 113, "relation": "per:children"}
{"text": "She is survived by her husband of 20 years , Thomas Brown ; a daughter , Emily ; and two sons , James and William .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Emily", "subj_start": 73, "subj_end": 78, "obj": "William", "obj_start": 106, "obj_end": 113, "relation": "per:children"}
{"text": "He is survived by his wife of 10 years , Sarah White ; a daughter , Lucy ; and a son , Henry .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Lucy", "subj_start": 68, "subj_end": 72, "obj": "Henry", "obj_start": 87, "obj_end": 92, "relation": "per:children"}
{"text": "John F. Kennedy was born in Brookline , Mass. , on May 29 , 1917 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "John F. Kennedy", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 15, "obj": "May 29 , 1917", "obj_start": 51, "obj_end": 64, "relation": "per:date_of_birth"}
{"text": "She was born on March 25 , 1985 in New York City .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "She", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 3, "obj": "March 25 , 1985", "obj_start": 16, "obj_end": 31, "relation": "per:date_of_birth"}
{"text": "He was born on April 12 , 1945 in Cincinnati , Ohio .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "He", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 2, "obj": "April 12 , 1945", "obj_start": 15, "obj_end": 30, "relation": "per:date_of_birth"}
{"text": "The company was founded on February 15 , 1995 in California .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "The company", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "February 15 , 1995", "obj_start": 27, "obj_end": 45, "relation": "per:date_of_birth"}
{"text": "The 2014 Winter Olympics in Sochi , Russia , were the first Winter Olympics to be held in the country .", "subj_type": "CITY", "obj_type": "COUNTRY", "subj": "Sochi", "subj_start": 28, "subj_end": 33, "obj": "Russia", "obj_start": 36, "obj_end": 42, "relation": "per:cities_of_residence"}
{"text": "The new CEO of Yahoo , Marissa Mayer , has a reputation for being a demanding boss , but she 's also known for her attention to detail and her ability to inspire her employees .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "TITLE", "subj": "Marissa Mayer", "subj_start": 23, "subj_end": 36, "obj": "CEO", "obj_start": 8, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "per:title"}
{"text": "As the first African American to serve as attorney general of the United States , Eric Holder has faced a number of challenges during his tenure , including the controversial \"fast and furious\" gun-running scandal .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "TITLE", "subj": "Eric Holder", "subj_start": 82, "subj_end": 93, "obj": "attorney general", "obj_start": 42, "obj_end": 58, "relation": "per:title"}
{"text": "After serving as a congressman for over a decade , Joe Crowley decided to run for the House Democratic leadership , but he lost to Nancy Pelosi .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "TITLE", "subj": "Joe Crowley", "subj_start": 51, "subj_end": 62, "obj": "congressman", "obj_start": 19, "obj_end": 30, "relation": "per:title"}
{"text": "As the first woman to serve as speaker of the House , Nancy Pelosi has been a powerful force in American politics for over two decades .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "TITLE", "subj": "Nancy Pelosi", "subj_start": 54, "subj_end": 66, "obj": "speaker", "obj_start": 31, "obj_end": 38, "relation": "per:title"}
{"text": "After serving as a senator for over a decade , Hillary Clinton decided to run for president , but she lost to Barack Obama .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "TITLE", "subj": "Hillary Clinton", "subj_start": 47, "subj_end": 62, "obj": "senator", "obj_start": 19, "obj_end": 26, "relation": "per:title"}
{"text": "As the first African American to serve as president of the United States , Barack Obama has made history and inspired a generation of young people to get involved in politics .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "TITLE", "subj": "Barack Obama", "subj_start": 75, "subj_end": 87, "obj": "president", "obj_start": 42, "obj_end": 51, "relation": "per:title"}
{"text": "As the mayor of New York City , Michael Bloomberg has been a controversial figure , known for his strong stance on gun control and his efforts to improve the city 's public health .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "TITLE", "subj": "Michael Bloomberg", "subj_start": 32, "subj_end": 49, "obj": "mayor", "obj_start": 7, "obj_end": 12, "relation": "per:title"}
{"text": "After serving as a governor for over a decade , Andrew Cuomo decided to run for the Senate , but he lost to a Republican challenger .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "TITLE", "subj": "Andrew Cuomo", "subj_start": 48, "subj_end": 60, "obj": "governor", "obj_start": 19, "obj_end": 27, "relation": "per:title"}
{"text": "She is survived by her husband of 50 years , John , and her parents , Mary and James .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "Mary", "subj_start": 70, "subj_end": 74, "obj": "James", "obj_start": 79, "obj_end": 84, "relation": "per:parents"}
{"text": "He is survived by his wife of 30 years , Jane , and his parents , John and Mary .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "PERSON", "subj": "John", "subj_start": 66, "subj_end": 70, "obj": "Mary", "obj_start": 75, "obj_end": 79, "relation": "per:parents"}
{"text": "The actor died of a heart attack at the age of 52 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CAUSE_OF_DEATH", "subj": "The actor", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 9, "obj": "heart attack", "obj_start": 20, "obj_end": 32, "relation": "per:cause_of_death"}
{"text": "The musician passed away due to liver failure .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CAUSE_OF_DEATH", "subj": "The musician", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 12, "obj": "liver failure", "obj_start": 32, "obj_end": 45, "relation": "per:cause_of_death"}
{"text": "The former president died of complications from a stroke .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CAUSE_OF_DEATH", "subj": "The former president", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 20, "obj": "complications from a stroke", "obj_start": 29, "obj_end": 56, "relation": "per:cause_of_death"}
{"text": "The athlete succumbed to cancer after a long battle .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CAUSE_OF_DEATH", "subj": "The athlete", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 11, "obj": "cancer", "obj_start": 25, "obj_end": 31, "relation": "per:cause_of_death"}
{"text": "The scientist died of a brain aneurysm at the age of 65 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CAUSE_OF_DEATH", "subj": "The scientist", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 13, "obj": "brain aneurysm", "obj_start": 24, "obj_end": 38, "relation": "per:cause_of_death"}
{"text": "The artist passed away due to a drug overdose .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CAUSE_OF_DEATH", "subj": "The artist", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 10, "obj": "drug overdose", "obj_start": 32, "obj_end": 45, "relation": "per:cause_of_death"}
{"text": "The politician died of a pulmonary embolism .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CAUSE_OF_DEATH", "subj": "The politician", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 14, "obj": "pulmonary embolism", "obj_start": 25, "obj_end": 43, "relation": "per:cause_of_death"}
{"text": "The philanthropist succumbed to a rare form of cancer at the age of 75 .", "subj_type": "PERSON", "obj_type": "CAUSE_OF_DEATH", "subj": "The philanthropist", "subj_start": 0, "subj_end": 18, "obj": "rare form of cancer", "obj_start": 34, "obj_end": 53, "relation": "per:cause_of_death"}
{"text": "The company has been a member of the Dow Jones Industrial Average since 1997 .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Dow Jones Industrial Average", "subj_start": 37, "subj_end": 65, "obj": "company", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "org:members"}
{"text": "The company is a member of the S&P 500 index .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "S&P 500 index", "subj_start": 31, "subj_end": 44, "obj": "company", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "org:members"}
{"text": "The league has 30 teams , each playing 82 games during the regular season .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "regular season", "subj_start": 59, "subj_end": 73, "obj": "league", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 10, "relation": "org:members"}
{"text": "The company is a member of the Fortune 500 list .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "Fortune 500 list", "subj_start": 31, "subj_end": 47, "obj": "company", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "org:members"}
{"text": "The team has won two NBA championships .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "NBA championships", "subj_start": 21, "subj_end": 38, "obj": "team", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 8, "relation": "org:members"}
{"text": "The company is a member of the NASDAQ stock exchange .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "NASDAQ stock exchange", "subj_start": 31, "subj_end": 52, "obj": "company", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 11, "relation": "org:members"}
{"text": "The league has 32 teams , each playing 16 games during the regular season .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "subj": "regular season", "subj_start": 59, "subj_end": 73, "obj": "league", "obj_start": 4, "obj_end": 10, "relation": "org:members"}
{"text": "The United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) was established in 1946 to provide humanitarian aid to children affected by World War II .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "UNICEF", "subj_start": 36, "subj_end": 42, "obj": "1946", "obj_start": 63, "obj_end": 67, "relation": "org:founded"}
{"text": "The World Health Organization (WHO) was established in 1948 to promote global health and prevent diseases .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "WHO", "subj_start": 31, "subj_end": 34, "obj": "1948", "obj_start": 55, "obj_end": 59, "relation": "org:founded"}
{"text": "The African Union (AU) was established in 2002 to promote economic, social, and political integration among African countries .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "AU", "subj_start": 19, "subj_end": 21, "obj": "2002", "obj_start": 42, "obj_end": 46, "relation": "org:founded"}
{"text": "The European Central Bank (ECB) was established in 1998 to manage the eurozone's monetary policy and maintain price stability .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "ECB", "subj_start": 27, "subj_end": 30, "obj": "1998", "obj_start": 51, "obj_end": 55, "relation": "org:founded"}
{"text": "The World Trade Organization (WTO) was established in 1995 to promote free trade and economic cooperation among nations .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "WTO", "subj_start": 30, "subj_end": 33, "obj": "1995", "obj_start": 54, "obj_end": 58, "relation": "org:founded"}
{"text": "The United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) was established in 1965 to eradicate poverty and reduce inequality in developing countries .", "subj_type": "ORGANIZATION", "obj_type": "DATE", "subj": "UNDP", "subj_start": 42, "subj_end": 46, "obj": "1965", "obj_start": 67, "obj_end": 71, "relation": "org:founded"}
